Hi, in this lesson, I will show you chart interface of course or for the detail.
You see the right panel. This is a chart where you can have conversations with AI.
You see it have a lot of controls. I will go through all of them in this lesson,
that you will understand how to use chart interface, how to use these controls,
to have the maximum productivity.
Let's start with a language model,
with this dropdown. You see, by default, it's at auto.
Resource says they choose the balance between quality and speed and recommend automatically
the best model for your tasks. You can do good off and you will be able to choose
any other model. Resource supports, you can also click on add models
and choose more models from a settings. This is the most popular models you can use.
Also, if you hover, you will see the tip. You can use also max mode to use more power for
to process your problems, your requests, but it's not always needed.
So, if you are not ready for media with these models, I recommend you to use auto.
As the next is a chart mode, you can use different chart modes, mode for different purposes.
So, cursor also makes some tips. I will cover all the modes in a separate lesson.
So, we will go through them in the tiles. They also will share with you some popular use cases
for these chart modes. Also, you are able to upload an image. For example, click on it, you can
paste, you can select a screenshot to be part of code or some documentation and restore
your analyze it as visual context, and you can ask some follow-up questions about it.
You see also send button, and there is an input where you can ask something. Also, when you
switch between modes, you might see the different text here as a placeholder and hint what you
can't do with these modes. Now, you can type any message right here, of me, read, you know,
some utility, et cetera, you can send a message. So, when you see the cursor generate and
the response asking some question, et cetera, I ask it just to show you how chat works.
What else you have? So, it's talk about prompt examples. You can use, you can watch, again,
the lesson from previous section about popular use cases of course, or for developers, where I
provided a lot of prompt examples. So, you can check it out. Also, if you talk about the chat mode,
you can create a new chat. For example, make sense to create a new chat if you want to work with,
if you want to ask some different questions, do some different tasks, so use, delete, every chat,
like every chat, you have a different type of tasks. You also can have some background
edges. So, you can read in documentation. I might be able to cover it later, but not in the
sections for the beginners. You can also have chat history. You see the previous chat history.
And you can also see the chat history if you create a new chat, and you see the past chats below,
so you can switch between them. For example, you can also click right here and switch between previous
chats. You also can hide secondary sidebar. They name it as a chat. And to see it again, you can
click on view, appearance, and click secondary sidebar right here. So, you can also click on three dots
to close chat. It's same as this button. You can clear all the chats. You can also export chat
to provide a feedback. You can also open a chat as editor. If you click on it, you will see a
much bigger chat. And you can, for example, move this window and have it within your files,
and you might have a lot of windows with a chat if you'd like it. So, I will close it and
you'll open the sidebar. Okay, that's great in your chat. You can also open a chat
settings. There are a few useful chat settings you might want to use. For example, there is, of
course, the default mode you want to use by default on every new chat. It's by default, it's
agent mode. You can also control textiles on auto clear chat like when you have the sound period of
connectivity. Also, provide some songs, scroll into the new messages. What is useful might be, for
example, let me check, include folder context. You can do it on. So, it will allow full content
of the sighted folder to be included in the context. For example, you'll provide a bigger context for
questions to the core story, but it also can use more tokens and sometimes you don't really need
this context. So, if you're sure you need it, so you can enable it. It's also a useful feature.
And also what is also nice feature, it's used only for agent mode, auto run mode, for example,
when you will ask something, some changes. Normally, the mode will show you it right here,
but if you enable this auto run, it will automatically apply everything to the files.
So, and you can also read more, more options for the chat. So, I hope this lesson was useful
to you and now you know the chat control interface. So, I'll see you in the next lesson.